louisianalottery.com 2013-12-26

# Louisiana Lottery Corporation

PRIVACY POLICY

Thank you for visiting the Louisiana Lottery Corporation's website and viewing our Privacy Policy.  We are strongly committed to maintaining the privacy of any personal information about you that is gathered during the use of our website. This policy outlines what information is collected from you when you visit any page on our domain (louisianalottery.com), including our mobile site and Facebook Pages, and the limited ways we use that information.

 **Information Collection & Usage**

There are two types of information that we collect, store and use: automatically collected information of a non-personal nature and personal information voluntarily submitted by users. The Louisiana Lottery does NOT collect any personally identifiable information from you when you visit this site, unless you expressly allow and/or voluntarily provide it such as filling out an online form; sending us an email; downloading/accepting the Louisiana Lottery?s Facebook "Contest Promotions" Application (App) or participating in a Facebook promotion via that application through the Lottery's Facebook Page; participating in a survey; joining Club Lotteaux; or enabling the global positioning system (GPS) functionality on your phone when accessing our mobile site.

 **I.   Automatically Collected Information**

When you visit our site, basic information is passively collected through your web browser. This information is non-personal and does not identify you specifically:

  * The Internet domain and IP address from which you accessed our site.
  * The type of browser, operating system and device used to access our site.
  * The date and time and length of your visit to our site.
  * The specific page(s) visited, graphics viewed and any documents downloaded.
  * If you accessed our site through another link on the Internet.
  * Any other statistical information systematically collected by Google Analytics.

 **How This Information is Used**

We will use automatically collected information to compile reports about popular pages and to see how users in aggregate are accessing our site. This information will help us to continue to improve the usability of our site so that users have a better experience when visiting our website. For example, if you visit our website via a mobile phone, you are directed to the mobile version of our site for a more device-friendly experience.

 **  
II.   Voluntarily Collected Information**

When you participate in various features of our website or Facebook Page, including sending the Lottery an email, accepting/downloading the Louisiana Lottery's Facebook "Contest Promotions" Application or entering a promotion via that application, you are voluntarily providing personally identifiable information. Participation in these features is strictly voluntary. Should you choose not to provide your personal information in these instances, it may limit your ability to fully participate in various features of our website or the Lottery's Facebook Page. However, it will not impair your ability to browse our website and access key Lottery consumer information. When you submit your personally identifiable information on the website or accept/download the Louisiana Lottery's Facebook "Contest Promotions" Application on its Facebook Page or enter promotions via the application, you are giving your consent to the collection, use and disclosure of this information as set forth in this Privacy Policy. If you would prefer that we not collect such information, please do not provide information or participate in such features of this website or the Lottery's Facebook Page.

 **How This Information is Used**

 _Joining the Louisiana Lottery's Players Club, Club Lotteaux_  
Personal information collected and maintained with Club Lotteaux membership is used to verify that the potential member is of the required age to participate. (See note about age requirement below.) Information about an individual's residence and game preferences is also used to customize Club Lotteaux pages with news and events most relevant to them. Email addresses will be used to communicate with members on an ad hoc basis and to fulfill their requests to participate in Club Lotteaux email lists. Changes to voluntarily collected information can be made by the user through the Change Profile feature of the site.  
 _  
Filling out a Survey_  
Personally identifiable information may be collected and used for marketing and product development purposes. Since drawings are sometimes held from among survey participants, personal information may be used in order to contact prize winners.  
 _ **  
**Accepting/Downloading the Louisiana Lottery's Facebook "Contest Promotions" Application_  
Personal information in your Facebook profile is collected when you download or accept the Louisiana Lottery's Facebook "Contest Promotions" Application (such as date of birth, phone number and address). This information is used to verify participants meet age and residency requirements as well as to contact contest winners. The information collected may change from time to time to allow the Lottery to better serve or market its services to its Facebook fans. When first accessing the App, you will be presented with a Facebook permissions page that advises you what Facebook profile information will be collected from you. You can then decide whether or not to share your Facebook information by accepting or not accepting the App. If you decide not to grant permission, you will not be able to use the App or participate in Lottery Facebook promotions. As a registered Facebook user, you are also subject to Facebook's Privacy Policy. Please check your Facebook account privacy settings for further information.

 _Participating in or Entering a Lottery Facebook Promotion_  
After downloading/accepting the Louisiana Lottery's Facebook "Contest Promotions" Application, you are allowed to enter contests and promotions the Lottery sponsors from time to time on its Facebook Page. When entering these contests, additional information may be voluntarily collected from you in order to determine contest eligibility or judge the contest according to its specific rules.

 _Requesting a Speaker Form_  
Personal information is used to enable us to contact you to book a Lottery speaker for your meeting or engagement.

 _Sending Us Email_  
Your email address and other information contained in or attached to your email are retained and used in order for us to respond to you. If you prefer we not collect or store this information, do not email us. Instead, communicate with us by phone or in person.

 _Taking the Problem Gambling Test_  
This form does NOT collect any personally identifiable information. Answers to the quiz are collected only to calculate and return the answer page. Data collected from this particular form is not stored.  
 _  
Using the "Find A Retailer" Page From a Mobile Device_  
If you access the "Find A Retailer" Page from a mobile device, you will be given the option to enable your device?s GPS in order to find a retailer(s) near your exact location. This information is used only to deliver tailored search results and is not stored. If you prefer not to share your location, utilize the zip code search option instead. Depending upon your device and settings, once you have granted permission to enable GPS, it may remain in effect until you change it. 

**User Age Requirements**  
The Louisiana Lottery does not knowingly collect information from children. Club Lotteaux registrants and Facebook promotion participants are required to be at least 21 years of age.

 **Dissemination of Information Collected**

The Louisiana Lottery is strongly committed to protecting personal information collected through the website against unauthorized access, use or disclosure. Consequently, personally identifiable information collected on this site or through the Louisiana Lottery's Facebook "Contest Promotions" Application is made readily available only to Louisiana Lottery employees or its consultants who need to know it in order to carry out their official functions including those outlined above. While the Louisiana Lottery may use personally identifiable information for marketing purposes, it will NOT sell, rent or trade this information to or with third parties.

Subject to applicable law, any information collected through our website or the Louisiana Lottery's Facebook "Contest Promotions" Application, or any information you provide to us through our website or the Louisiana Lottery's Facebook "Contest Promotions" Application may be considered public record.  We may be required, therefore, to provide such information for public inspection. For example, if anyone requests the names of all Louisiana Lottery Club Lotteaux members, we may have to provide the names under Louisiana's public records law.

The Lottery may also choose to release information in aggregate collected for statistical purposes as long as it is in a form that cannot be used to identify a particular person.

 **Retention of Collected Information**

The information collected through our website is retained by the Louisiana Lottery in accordance with the records retention and disposition requirements of state law. In general, information submitted online is kept for a minimum of three years.

 **  
Security**

The Louisiana Lottery utilizes industry standards with respect to safeguarding the integrity of its computer systems, networks and this website, including but not limited to individual authentication, the security of transmitted data, security monitoring, prevention of data corruption and auditing. We believe these measures provide reasonable protection of private information in our possession; however we do not ensure, guarantee or warrant the transmission of your personal information through our website.

 **Cookies**

Some pages on the Louisiana Lottery's website utilize cookies. Cookies are simple text files that are stored on your computer by Internet websites. They do not contain personally identifiable information and do not compromise your privacy or security. The Louisiana Lottery may use such cookies from time to time to customize or enhance your browsing experience or for other purposes such as indicating whether a particular survey has already been completed by a Club Lotteaux member to avoid duplication of responses.

 **Other Sites**

This Privacy Policy applies only to web pages and Facebook promotions hosted by the Louisiana Lottery. For your convenience, links to other sites of interest are a part of this website. If you choose to access these links, you should read that entity's privacy policy to determine its practices since we are not responsible for their content.

 **Changes to this Policy**

The Louisiana Lottery may revise this Privacy Policy from time to time without notifying you. However, revised policies will be posted here, with the amended date located at the bottom of the page. You may wish to review this policy periodically, as any information collected on this site will be subject to the policy in place at that time.

 **Contacting the Lottery**

If you should have any questions about our Privacy Policy, the practices of this site or your dealings with this site, or if you believe that your personal information is being used for a purpose other than what is outlined in this policy, please contact the Louisiana Lottery Corporation at 555 Laurel Street, Baton Rouge, LA  70801 or by emailing info@louisianalottery.com.

 **  
** _Rev. 8/10/2012_
